{
    "data":[
    { "id":1,
      "question":"Command to check the ip of a dns?",
      "answer":"You can use tool like dig, by using the this command: dig dnsname",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":2,
      "question":"How to list all hidden files in linux?",
      "answer":"This command can do it. ls -a",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":3,
      "question":"Which tool do you use to search in a file?",
      "answer":"grep",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":4,
      "question":"How to check if port is reachable?",
      "answer":"telnet IP PORT",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":5,
      "question": "What are the three numbers in load average?",
      "answer":"First number is load average for 1 min second is for 5 and third is for 15 min.",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":6,
        "question": "What do you mean by load average?",
        "answer":"Load average stands for the total number of tasks waiting for CPU in queue. In other words the number of tasks that are not getting CPU resource.",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":7,
        "question": "What is the signal used to kill process forcefully?",
        "answer":"kill -9 processid. This is also called SIGKILL(9)",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":8,
        "question": "What is the signal used to kill process gracefully?",
        "answer":"kill -15 processid. This is also called SIGTERM(15)",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":9,
        "question": "How to create an empty file?",
        "answer":"touch filenaem",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":10,
        "question": "How to check free memory?",
        "answer":"free -m",
        "link":""
    }

  ]
}
  